Name: Maina Peter Waruru.

D.O.B: 28-8-1995

Tel.:0723440442.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pierre-waruru

Email:mainapeter008@gmail.com.

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE.

Personable IT technical Specialist with 3+ years expertise, majoring on hardware and software and system management, network troubleshooting, IT equipment maintenance and monitoring where I will be able to utilise my acquired skills to maximize production in your organization.

## PROFILE SUMMARY.

Highly knowledgeable and self-driven Information Technology graduate, with adequate skills in Computer Networking, comprehensive knowledge in the latest technology, IT software and systems, system development and handling technical problems related to ICT.

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS.

- IT Technical Specialist. (Hardware troubleshooting, software development and maintance)
- IT tech support(backend and front end support)
- Website design and Application programming (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Android).
- Proficient in Windows 7, 8; Windows Server 2003, 2008, 2012; Linux including, Ubuntu, Arch, Debian, and Kali Linux.
- Network troubleshooting.
- Operating System and software Set up and maintenance.
- Database administration.
- Passionate IT trainer.

## PERSONAL SKILLS.

- Excellent verbal and written communication skills.
- Eloquent communication and organization skills.
- Dynamic and willing to learn.
- Excellent interpersonal skills
- I am Friendly
- I am Energetic & Enthusiastic
- I am Compassionate & Empathetic
- I am Up To Date on Technological Understanding

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE.**

### **Computer Trainer**

Tutor at Topaz Driving School

#### **Key Responsibility**

- Prepare all training material for courses, including PowerPoint presentations, skill exploration and exercises, and assessment.
- Delivered classroom based training on the Microsoft suite of products such as Microsoft Office, Excel, Access, and PowerPoint for entry-level students.
- Created classroom materials to facilitate skills training.
- Developed practice exercises for experiential learners.

#### **ICT** tutor

March 2019-September 2019

Tutor at Kipipiri Technical and Vocational Center-

Taught the ICT students Operating System, C programming and calculus.

Handled hardware and software maintenance in the computer laboratory.

Provided support in monitoring and setting up of computer equipment to students and faculty.

#### **Key Responsibility**

- Delivered classroom based training on the Microsoft suite of products such as Microsoft Office, Excel, Access, and PowerPoint for entry-level technical staff.
- Created classroom materials to facilitate skills training.
- Developed practice exercises for experiential learners.
- Gave feedback to class participants and provided individual coaching as needed.
- Provided assistance to the support department with end-user refresher training.

#### **ICT** tutor

#### February 2021-February 2022

Tutor at Premier Professional institute, Limuru and Kikuyu Campus where i taught student on various levels. My main duty is to teach ICT to Diploma In ICT students, Hospitality and Electrical students and also the to the Craft in ICT students.

#### **Key Responsibility**

- Assessed the training needs of individuals as well as work teams.
- Created lesson plans.
- Implemented course progressions and programs students.
- Trained staff on the use of Microsoft reporting system software with Microsoft database and associated reporting tools.
- Taught Microsoft Office courses to Short courses student physically and remotely using video conferencing.
- Advanced personal IT Skills and updated training courses including new product functionality.

#### Sales Representatives, Safaricom PLC

- Selling Sim cards on commission based terms
- Meet the target set by the sales manager.
- Assist Customers with network and gadget related problems.
- Updated the customers on the latest products and services from Safaricom.

## **IT Technical Support**

March 2022-July 2022

zandaux.com

#### **Key Responsibility**

- Identified hardware and software solutions.
- Troubleshooting technical issues.
- Diagnosed and repairing faults.
- Resolving network issues.
- Installing and configuring hardware and software.
- Speaking to customers to quickly get to the root of their problem.
- Provided timely and accurate customer feedback.
- Talking customers through a series of actions to resolve a problem.
- Did follow up with clients to ensure the problem is resolved.
- Replacing or repairing the necessary parts.
- Supporting the roll-out of new applications.
- Provided support in the form of procedural documentation.
- Managed multiple cases at one time.
- Testing and evaluating new technologies.
- Conducting electrical safety checks on equipment.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Science in Information technology**

Karatina University 2015-2020

## **Key Skills**

- Software Troubleshooting & Problem Solving.
- IT Skills
- Communication & Interpersonal Skills
- Creative Thinking Skills

# Nyahururu High School (KCSE)

2011-2014 Grade B 66points

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Huawei CISCO training. Computer INFO security training.

Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer

#### **INTERESTS AND HOBBIES**

Computer training.

Sports especially football, I am a talented footballer

# Referees

Charles Ndung'u

Topaz driving and Computer college

Tel. 0705829897

Madam Wangechi

H.o.d ICT +254725686803

Mr. Edwin Rono

Sales manager,

zandaux.com

0725563537

Mr. Goddifrey Mbudo

Premier Professional Institute

0712821795

James Karugu

CTO,

zandaux.com

0790788769



To whom it may concern,

#### REF: RECOMMENDATION LETTER FOR PETER WARURU

I am writing to recommend Peter Waruru for the position in your company. During his time at Zandaux.com, he has displayed great skills in ICT support skills, I have been impressed by his leadership skill, time management and he's success oriented. He is a good communicator which made him interact well with colleague and clients. He's a proficient IT technician, which makes him the right candidate.

Peter is always professional and works hard to have an answer for every person who turns to him for help. While making his job personal is not the best plan, Peter still takes his performance personally and constantly works to improve himself. Peter would also be willing to put in long hours to make sure that all of our projects were completed properly and that we got the results we were looking for

I am absolutely confident that Peter would be a great fit for your company. Not only will he bring the kind of skills and experience you're looking for, but also will become a great asset to your company.

If you need more information or specific examples, please do not hesitate to contact me at (0725563537).

Sincerely,

Edwin Rono Sales Manager,

Zandaux.com